<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), Water Monitoring &amp; Standards (WMS), Bureau of Water Quality Standards and Assessment (BWQSA)</origin><pubdate>201709</pubdate><title>Integrated List of Waters for New Jersey, 2014 (Integrated List), Edition 201709 (Envr_mon_water_IR_2014_use)</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Trenton, NJ</pubplace><publish>NJ Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP)</publish></pubinfo><othercit>The NJDEP may distribute GIS data in a variety of formats, such as the ESRI shapefile and/or various versions of the file geodatabase format.  The data also may be available for viewing on various profiles of the NJ GeoWeb online mapping application.</othercit><onlink>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/listall.html</onlink><onlink>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</onlink><lworkcit><citeinfo><origin>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection</origin><pubdate>2014</pubdate><title>2014 NJ Integrated Water Quality Monitoring and Assessment Report (Integrated Report)</title><pubinfo><pubplace>Trenton, NJ</pubplace><publish>NJDEP</publish></pubinfo><othercit>The 2014 Integrated List of Waters is published as Appendix A of the 2014 Integrated Report</othercit><onlink>http://www.state.nj.us/dep/wms/bwqsa/2014_final_IR_complete.pdf</onlink></citeinfo></lworkcit></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>
This data consists of the 2014 New Jersey Integrated List of Waters (Integrated List) prepared as Appendix A of the 2014 NJ Integrated Water Quality Monitoring and Assessment Report. This data represents the results of assessing NJ's 958 assessment units to determine if applicable designated use(s) was(were) attained.

The data reflects which of five sublists each assessment/designated use combination was assigned:

Sublist 1- All applicable designated uses were assessed and attained (with the exception of Fish Consumption)
Sublist 2- The applicable designated use was attained.
Sublist 3- Insufficient data was available to assess use attainment.
Sublist 4- The designated use was not attained but a TMDL or other measures are being implemented to improve water quality.
Sublist 5- The designated use was not attained and a TMDL is required.
			</abstract><purpose>This data set spatially represents the use assessment results for the 2014 NJ Integrated Water Quality Monitoring and Assessment Report, which is prepared by the Department pursuant to Section 305(b) of the federal Clean Water Act.</purpose><supplinf>Data is current.</supplinf></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>20020101</begdate><enddate>2014</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><current>ground condition</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-75.587306</westbc><eastbc>-73.890363</eastbc><northbc>41.357565</northbc><southbc>38.874880</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>inlandWaters</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>none</themekt><themekey>2014 Integrated List of Waters</themekey><themekey>Use Assessments</themekey><themekey>Designated Use</themekey><themekey>Water Quality Inventory</themekey><themekey>305 (b)</themekey><themekey>Water Quality Assessment</themekey><themekey>Statewide Water Quality</themekey><themekey>water</themekey><themekey>monitoring</themekey><themekey>assessment</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>User</themekt><themekey>Envr_mon_water_IR_2014_use</themekey><themekey>ir_2014_designateduse</themekey></theme><place><placekt>none</placekt><placekey>New Jersey</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>
New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP)

Data Use and Distribution Agreement

I. DESCRIPTION OF DATA TO BE PROVIDED

Before receiving and/or using NJDEP data layers, the user agrees to abide by the terms and conditions of the following:

SUBJECT DATA LAYERS
For all data contained herein, (NJDEP) makes no representations of any kind, including, but not limited to, the warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular use, nor are any such warranties to be implied with respect to the digital data layers furnished hereunder. NJDEP assumes no responsibility to maintain them in any manner or form.

II. TERMS OF AGREEMENT

1. Digital data received from the NJDEP are to be used solely for internal purposes in the conduct of daily affairs.
2. The data are provided, as is, without warranty of any kind and the user is responsible for understanding the accuracy limitations of all digital data layers provided herein, as documented in the associated metadata file. Any reproduction or manipulation of the above data must ensure that the coordinate reference system remains intact and any data manipulation documented in the metadata by the user.  NJDEP assumes no responsibility for any reproduction or data manipulation done by the user.
3. Digital data received from the NJDEP may not be reproduced or redistributed for use by anyone without first obtaining permission from the NJDEP via email gisnet@dep.state.nj.us.  This clause is not intended to restrict distribution of printed mapped information produced from the digital data.
4. Any maps, publications, reports, or other documents produced as a result of this project that utilize NJDEP digital data will credit the NJDEP's Geographic Information System (GIS) as the source of the data with the following credit/disclaimer:   "This (map/publication/report) was developed using New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection Geographic Information System digital data, but this secondary product has not been verified by NJDEP and is not state-authorized."
5. Users shall require any independent contractor, hired to undertake work that will utilize digital data obtained from the NJDEP, to agree not to use, reproduce, or redistribute NJDEP GIS data for any purpose other than the specified contractual work. All copies of NJDEP GIS data utilized by an independent contractor will be required to be returned to the original user at the close of such contractual work.   Users hereby agree to abide by the use and reproduction conditions specified above and agree to hold any independent contractor to the same terms. By using data provided herein, the user acknowledges that terms and conditions have been read and that the user is bound by these criteria.
		</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Water Monitoring</cntorg><cntper>Lager, Leigh</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Geographic Information Systems Specialist 1</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>35 Arctic Pkwy Eshap/Land Use</address><city>Ewing Twp</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08638</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>609-292-0427</cntvoice><cntemail>Leigh.Lager@dep.nj.gov</cntemail><cntinst>via email</cntinst></cntinfo></ptcontac><browse><browsen>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/digidownload/images/ir2010/ir_2014_designateduse.gif</browsen><browsed>image</browsed><browset>GIF</browset></browse></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>Tests conducted to confirm attribute accuracy.</attraccr></attracc><logic>Tests conducted to confirm topological accuracy of 958 polygons were closed.</logic><complete>Unknown</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>
Layer was derived from the HUC14 coverage. Positional Accuracy for Huc14 states:

NJGS received sub-huc14 basins coverage from USGS-WRD in NAD27 UTM coordinates and began processing into Dephuc14 in NAD83 State Plane Feet coordinates. Projection resulted in a coverage that was shifted about 735 ft SSW in comparison to earlier coverages. The reason for, and origin of this shift is unknown. Therefore, the projected coverage was manually transformed using an affine transformation to best fit the correct line positions based on a comparison to earlier version of the dephuc14 coverage.

Alterations were made to the huc14 boundaries in the area of Barnegat Bay and the Delaware River to better represent assessment unit areas.
				</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), New Jersey Geological Survey (NJGS)</origin><pubdate>20060120</pubdate><title>NJDEP 14 Digit Hydrologic Unit Code delineations for New Jersey (DEPHUC14)</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Trenton, NJ</pubplace><publish>Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), New Jersey Geological Survey (NJGS)</publish></pubinfo><onlink>http://www.state.nj.us/dep/gis/digidownload/zips/statewide/dephuc14.zip</onlink></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>24000</srcscale><typesrc>online</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>200701</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><srccurr>ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>HUC14</srccitea><srccontr>data was taken from DEP HUC14 data</srccontr></srcinfo><procstep><procdesc>The NJ HUC 14 coverage was used as a base layer.</procdesc><procdate>200701</procdate></procstep><procstep><procdesc>The 2012 Integrated List result tables were joined to the modified HUC14 coverage. This step updated the coverage to the most recent use assessment results.</procdesc><procdate>201503</procdate></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Imported the 2010 Integrated List Metadata and edited it to support the 2012 Integrated List dataset.</procdesc><procdate>201503</procdate></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Altered AU boundaries to conform with AU used in 2014 Integrated Report.  Now 958 polygons.  Imported the 2012 Integrated List Metadata and edited it to support the 2014 Integrated List dataset.</procdesc><procdate>201709</procdate></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><sdtsterm><sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype><ptvctcnt>958</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System 1983</gridsysn><spcs><spcszone>2900</spcszone></spcs></gridsys><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.002048</absres><ordres>0.002048</ordres></coordrep><plandu>survey feet</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222</denflat></geodetic></horizsys><vertdef><altsys/></vertdef></spref><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>NJDEP/OIRM/Bureau of GIS</cntorg><cntper>GIS Help Desk</cntper></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>401 East State Street</address><city>Trenton</city><state>NJ</state><postal>08625</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>(609) 777-0672</cntvoice><cntfax>(609) 292-7900</cntfax><cntemail>gisnet@dep.state.nj.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><distliab>This organization provides the geographic data "as is".  This organization makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of information contained in the geographic data.  Also, this organization makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of the product or its fitness for any particular purpose.  The burden for determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user.  Although these files have been processed successfully on computers at this organization, no warranty is made by this organization regarding the use of these data on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply any such warranty.  See also "Use Constraints" for additional distribution and/or data use requirements.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>DEP distributes ESRI .SHP and/or GDB. Some data may be NJ GeoWeb "display only" layers.</formname><formvern>latest version</formvern><filedec>WinZip</filedec></digtinfo><digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka><networkr>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/listall.html</networkr><networkr>http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</networkr></networka></computer></onlinopt><offoptn><offmedia>None</offmedia><recfmt>None</recfmt></offoptn></digtopt></digform><fees>None</fees><ordering>All available NJDEP public GIS data can be downloaded for free.  Some data shown in NJGeoWeb application may not yet be available for download due to various data or distribution issues.  Please email gisnet@dep.state.nj.us with any data distribution questions.</ordering></stdorder><custom>
The NJDEP may distribute GIS data in a variety of formats, such as the ESRI shapefile and/or various versions of the file geodatabase format.  The data also may be available for viewing on various profiles of the NJ GeoWeb online mapping application.  

Note: Some older NJDEP data may not contain .prj files due to distribution procedures at that time. If download does not contain a .prj, please download from:

http://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/njsp83.zip 

Please rename .prj to the name of the downloadable filename. (for example: If Head of Tides filename is HOT.shp, please rename .prj to HOT.prj).  This allows ESRI software to recognize the projection information.
		</custom></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20150303</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Leigh Lager</cntper><cntorg>NJDEP WMS BWQSA</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>GIS Specialist 1</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>401 E. State Street</address><address>P.O. Box 420</address><city>Trenton.</city><state>New Jersey</state><postal>08625-0409</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>(609) 292-0427</cntvoice><cntemail>leigh.lager@dep.nj.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc><metextns><onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo><Esri><CreaDate>20180419</CreaDate><CreaTime>12521600</CreaTime><ArcGISstyle>FGDC CSDGM Metadata</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><copyHistory><copy source="\\dep-tcshared\shared\gis\data\Data_Team_Review\Integrated_Report\Metadata\Envr_mon_water_IR_2014" dest="\\2CXONM1\F$\GIS_Projects\Intergrated_Report\Metadata\Envr_mon_water_IR_2014" date="20170921" time="14502600"></copy></copyHistory></DataProperties><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat></Esri><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypd>2014 NJ Integrated List of Waters</enttypd><enttypds>NJDEP</enttypds><enttypl>ir_2014_designateduse</enttypl></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AU_num</attrlabl><attrdef>Assessment Unit numbers/code</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>unique entry</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AU_name</attrlabl><attrdef>NJ DEP Assessment Unit Name</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>unique entry</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>HUC14TXT</attrlabl><attrdef>Assessment Unit numbers/code - text</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>unique entry</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>WMA</attrlabl><attrdef>Watershed Management  Area</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>unique entry</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AquaticLife_General</attrlabl><attrdef>Designated Use Aquatic Life General</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>See Entity and Attribute Overview for Value Definitions</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AquaticLife_Trout</attrlabl><attrdef>Designated Use Aquatic Life Use Trout</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>See Entity and Attribute Overview for Value Definitions</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>FishConsumption</attrlabl><attrdef>Designated Use Fish Consumption</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>See Entity and Attribute Overview for Value Definitions</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Recreation</attrlabl><attrdef>Designated Use Recreation (Primary and Secondary Contact)</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>See Entity and Attribute Overview for Value Definitions</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shellfish</attrlabl><attrdef>Designated Use Shellfish Harvest for Consumption</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>See Entity and Attribute Overview for Value Definitions</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PublicWaterSupply</attrlabl><attrdef>Designated Use Drinking Water Supply</attrdef><attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>See Entity and Attribute Overview for Value Definitions</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl><attrdef>Length of feature.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr></detailed><overview><eaover>
This data includes all the assessment unit/designated use combinations that resulted from assessing NJ's assessment units (AUs) to determine if applicable designated use were attained. The data reflects which of five sublists of the Integrated List each AU/designated use combination was assigned:

Sublist 1- All applicable designated uses were assessed and attained (with the exception of Fish Consumption)
Sublist 2- The applicable designated use was attained.
Sublist 3- Insufficient data was available to assess use attainment.
Sublist 4- The designated use was not attained but a TMDL or other measures are being implemented to improve water quality.
Sublist 5- The designated use was not attained and a TMDL is required.
N/A was assigned to the respective sublist for each AU/designated use combination where the use did not apply.

Note: Attribute headings may be truncated in Shapefile format. Additionally, the attribute OBJECTID is changed to FID in the Shapefile format.
			</eaover><eadetcit>NJ 2014 Integrated List of Waters</eadetcit><eadetcit>NJ 2014 Integrated Water Quality Monitoring and Assessment Methods</eadetcit><eadetcit>NJ 2014 Integrated Water Quality Monitoring and Assessment Report</eadetcit></overview></eainfo></metadata>
